

Contacts

Phone +351 964815670

☑ Email vladvaz@gmail.com

● Location Castelo Branco, PT

in LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/vladimiro-vaz

G GitHub
github.com/vladvaz

Skills

Angular

C#

C++

F#

HTML

Java Ocaml

PostgreSQL

React

SASS

Scala

Typescript

VLADIMIRO JOÃO DOS SANTOS VAZ

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PROFILE

My educational background includes a degree in Computer Science from UBI. I embarked on my professional journey in 2019 at Capgemini, where I initially worked as a front-end developer. In this role, I utilized Angular to create applications for infotainment systems in Volkswagen vehicles. During my tenure at Capgemini, I also contributed to various other projects, leveraging technologies such as React, Redux, SASS (for front-end development), and MySQL, Node.js, and C++ (for back-end development).In 2021, I embraced a new challenge at Devoteam, working on a project for Vaudoise Assurances as a full-stack developer. The project involved migrating an older Angular.js codebase to a more recent version. Additionally, I implemented new features for internal tools used by company employees. My toolkit for this endeavor included Angular (for front-end) and .NET (for back-end). Since January 2023, I have held a position at Blip.pt, where I focus on developing internal tools to enhance the efficiency of risk trading teams. My work involves creating micro front-end applications using React and other relevant libraries. Furthermore, I take on the responsibility of onboarding and mentoring fellow colleagues, supporting their skill development.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Blip.pt

January 2023 - Present

- Creating new micro-frontend applications to enhance the efficiency of risk trading teams. Improving existing applications and mentoring new collegues.
- Creation of new micro-frontend applications, following the rules defined by the design team;
- Aligning the work to be done with project owners, backend team and design team;
- Integration with the backend services;
- Configuration and deploy of new services;
- Creation of unit tests, acceptance tests, E2E tests and contract tests;
- Migration and updating of old pages with new features;
- Bug fixes and code reviews;
- Technical debt reduction;
- · Mentoring associate colleagues.

React Typescript Jest Sass Playwright AWS Ansible Buildkite Kubernetes

Docker

Full-stack developer

Devoteam

December 2021 - December 2022

- Migration and improvement of an existing web application, used by employees and customers of a swiss insurance company.
- Creation of new pages, following the rules defined by the design team;
- Integration with the backend services;
- Creation of npm libraries to interact with several microservices;
- Migration and updating of old pages with new features;
- Bug fixes and code reviews;
- Technical debt reduction;
- Creation of unit tests and documentation.

Angular Typescript Ngxs Rxjs Jasmine SASS C# .Net

Languages

Portuguese - C2

English - C1

French - A2

Hobbies

Game development

Cinema

Playing guitar

Going to the gym

Front-end developer Capgemini Engineering

August 2019 - December 2021

- Development of a music player for infotainment systems in vehicles, using web technologies.
- Creation of new pages, following the rules defined by the design team;
- Creating transitions and micro-interactions on pages;
- Integration with backend services;
- Creation of unit tests and documentation.

Angular Typescript Rxjs Jasmine SASS Nest.js

Full-stack developer

Capgemini Engineering

October 2020 - January 2021



- Web application creation;
- Creating new components in React;
- Defining style sheets with SASS;
- Creating and managing the global state of the application using the Redux library;
- · Creating and validating forms;
- Development of backend services;
- Creating a REST API using Express and Node.js;
- Creation and maintenance of a database using MySQL;
- Creating unit tests and documentation.

React Redux React Router React Hook Form TypeScript Jest Node.js

MySQL SASS

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

Universidade da Beira Interior - FE 2016 - 2019

Master's Degree in Civil Engineering

Universidade de Coimbra - FCTUC 2007 - 2013

CERTIFICATES

Machine Learning with Python

Coursera 2021/12/20

www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/W8QGP7J9KJ8J

Big Data Analysis with Scala and Spark

Coursera 2021/07/12

www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/YZ2EJYPWA869

Functional Programming Principles in Scala

Coursera 2021/06/08

www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/67R2MKQGZDTQ